Anderson Piffer

Senior Game Designer & Product Manager

+55 11 99254-0970 4piffer@gmail.com Skype: a.piffer https://apiffer.com

COVER LETTER

Hi, I'm Andy! As a former **Game Designer** I've created more than 50 fun casual mobile games that made millions of people smile worldwide. Afterwards, as a **Product Manager**, I've led teams of up to 20 creative minds – from discovery to live-ops phases – into building popular and profitable games through goal oriented, iterative, collaborative, and data-informed processes. My favorite and most successful projects were <u>leading Logic Pic</u>, an "abandoned" 3 years old puzzle, into a marketable and profitable game by experimenting systems, progression, and monetization strategies; and <u>designing My Boo</u>, a tamagotchi-style game downloaded by more than 40 million players and surpassed a million dollar revenue mark.

For the last couple of months I've been on a sabbatical journey in Europe and Southeast Asia, where I've volunteered in NGOs by applying my design and language skills to help children in need while learning from the cultural exchange on both professional and personal level.

I'm currently looking for an opportunity to join a team as a **Senior Game Designer**, ideally in the mobile game industry and as a remote "work-from-home" position.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Manager, Tapps Games, January 2016 – July 2019

Co-created and led product strategy and game direction with the team and stakeholders using agile and lean methodologies. Managed a roadmap of prioritized opportunities and A/B experiments supported by OKRs, business and partnership goals, market analysis, players' feedback, KPIs and in-game analytics. Furthermore, I've also mentored people from the Product and Game Design team and kickstarted new processes that drastically improve Tapps' research and production phases.

Highlights: Led more than 20 people into discovery, production and soft-launch of "Decor Dream", a hybrid Match-3 with 3D Decoration game (2018–2019), and led multiple squads into making successful live-ops releases for Cow Evolution (2016), Vlogger Go Viral (2016), My Boo (2016–2017), and Logic Pic (2017).

Game Designer, Tapps Games, July 2013 - December 2015

Designed and balanced core-loops, systems, levels, economies, and/or updates for more than 50 casual mobile games of different genres, including successful ones such as My Boo. In order to deliver that many releases, I've collaborated with different designers, artists, developers, QAs, sound designers, plus mentored two junior game designers, and created a few dev-tools.

Design Intern, Tapps Games, August 2011 - August 2012

Pitched and documented new games proposals; designed game levels and user interface.

EDUCATION & RELEVANT EXPERIENCES

Volunteer, Safe Place Mission (NGO), Cambodia, May 2020 - October 2020

- Taught English to children/teenagers using custom designed activities, toys and games
- Collaborated with the management to improve some of their program processes
- Created the <u>official website</u> and <u>campaign program video</u>

Immersive Program in Creative Leadership, Polifonia, August 2018 - December 2018

Bachelor's Degree in Game Design, Universidade Anhembi Morumbi (UAM), 2009 – 2012

- Designed tabletop games and playable prototypes using different technologies
- Published an undergraduate research on Game UX Design (Cognitive Usability)
- Final thesis focusing on Game System Design (Resource Management and Strategy)

Drawing Workshop, Pacearte Studio, 2008 - 2011

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Documentation & management: Microsoft Office, Google Suite, JIRA, Confluence, Trello.
- Game development: Excel/Spreadsheets, Unity3D, Photoshop, Illustrator, Maya.
- Programming (intermediate): Unity3D C#, LUA, HTML, JS, CSS and GIT code-management.
- Data analysis: iTunes Connect, Google Suite (Play Console, Analytics, Firebase), Tableau, Facebook Analytics, Sensor Tower, App Annie and Game Refinery.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Brazilian Portuguese: Native
English: Fluent